Inventory of the Carter Family Papers 1667-1862
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Carter Family Papers, 1667-1862.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 C24
8,609 items.
The collection includes correspondence, accounts, diaries, and land records of various members of the Carter and Taylor families including the following: Robert "King" Carter (1663- 1732); Robert Carter (1704-1731) and Landon Carter (1710-1778), sons of Robert "King" Carter (1663-1732); Robert Carter (1728-1804), son of Robert Carter (1704-1731); Robert Wormeley Carter (1734-1804), son of Landon Carter of Sabine Hall; and Landon Carter (1757-1820), grandson of Robert Carter.
Carter Family,; Taylor Family,; Robert Carter, 1663-1732.; Robert Carter, 1704- 1731.; Landon Carter, 1710-1778.; Robert Wormeley Carter, 1734-1797.; Robert Carter, 1728-1804.; Landon Carter, 1757-1820.; Robert Wormeley Carter, 1792-1861.; Robley Dunglison, 1798-1869.; John Tyler, 1790-1862.; John Tayloe Lomax, 1781-1862.; Edmund Ruffin, 1794-1865.; Robert Young Conrad, 1805- 1875.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 8,602, 12/31/1935.
Purchased: 2 items, 11/00/1938.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert "King" Carter (1663-1732) was a colonial official and great landholder (300,000 acres). His sons were Robert Carter (1704-1731) and Landon Carter (1710-1778) of "Sabine Hall." Grandsons of Robert Carter included Robert "Councillor" Carter (1728-1804) of "Nomini" and Robert Wormeley Carter (1734-1797).
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes: correspondence and land records of Robert "King" Carter; correspondence and land records of his sons Robert Carter (1704-1731) and Landon Carter(1710-1778); correspondence, accounts, land records and the appointment to the Virginia Council of Robert Carter (1728-1804), son of Robert Carter (1704-1731); correspondence, diaries, land records and accounts of Robert Wormeley Carter (1734-1804), son of Landon Carter of Sabine Hall; and correspondence and land records and papers concerning the estate of Robert Carter's grandson, Landon Carter (1757-1820).
The bulk of the collection consists of the papers of Robert Wormeley Carter (1792-1861)including his correspondence with Robley Dunglison, John Tyler, John Tayloe Lomax, Edmund Ruffin, Robert Young Conrad and members of the Tayloe family as well as his diaries and accounts arranged by subject.
Subjects covered in the collection include plantation life, horse-racing, land, nineteenth-century Virginia politics, slavery, and tobacco. In addition, there are miscellaneous eighteenth-century land and legal documents.
Arrangement
Arrangement
All papers which could be definitely identified with a person of some importance are grouped under the name of that person. These groups are arranged by alphabetical order. Persons of the same name are distinguished by dates of birth and death, or by their relationship to other persons whose dates are known.
The general files (Folder 103-109) are placed after this alphabetical series (Folders 1-102). These files are seperated into catorgories using appropriate classifications.
Letters and papers belonging to estates, suits, etc., are filed with their respective groups. Likewise other letters and papers are listed either in the alphabetically arranged groups mentioned above, or in the general files.
Organization
This collection is organized into the following series and subseries:
Series 1: People Files
Subseries 1: Carter, Miss
Subseries 2: Carter, (Miss C.)
Subseries 3: Carter (Charles) of Cleve, 1707-1764.
Subseries 4: Carter (Charles) of Shirley, 1732-1806.
Subseries 5: Carter (Elizabeth) [wife of Landon Carter, 1710-1778]
Subseries 6: Carter (Elizabeth) [daughter of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861]
Subseries 7: Carter (Elizabeth L.) [sister of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861]
Subseries 8: Carter (George) [son of Robert "Councillor" Carter]
Subseries 9: Carter (George B.) estate
Subseries 10: Carter (John Armistead) guardianship
Subseries 11: Carter (Kate)
Subseries 12: Carter (Landon) 1710-1778
Subseries 13: Carter (Landon, Jr.) [son of Landon Carter, 1710-1778]
Subseries 14: Carter (Landon) 1756-1820, estate
Subseries 15: Carter (Landon, Jr.) [half-brother of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861]
Subseries 16: Carter (Robert "King") 1663-1732
Subseries 17: Carter (Robert) of Nomini, born c. 1704, died 1731
Subseries 18: Carter (Robert "Councillor") of Nomini, 1728-1804
Subseries 19: Carter (Robert Wormeley) 1734-1797
Subseries 20: Carter (Robert W.) 1792-1861
Subseries 21: Carter (Robert W.) 1792-1861
Subseries 22: Tayloe (John) estate
Series 2: General files
Subseries 1: Accounts, invoices, receipts
Subseries 2: Letters
Subseries 3: Other papers
Subseries 4: Printed matter
Subseries 5: Unidentified pieces and fragments
Subseries 6: Labels, covers and envelopes
Additional Indexing Material
Other Finding Aid
This current finding aid is also available in the microfilm format at the Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
An additional index can be found at: National Inventory of Documentary Sources in the United States available from Chadwyck-Healey, Inc., 1021 Prince Street, Alexandria, Va. 22314.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Carter family.; Taylor family.
Persons:
Carter, Robert, 1663- 1732.; Carter, Robert, 1704-1731.; Carter, Landon, 1710-1778.; Carter, Robert Wormeley, 1734-1797.; Carter, Robert, 1728-1804.; Carter, Landon, 1757-1820.; Carter, Robert Wormeley, 1792-1861.; Dunglison, Robley, 1798- 1869.; Tyler, John, 1790-1862.; Lomax, John Tayloe, 1781-1862.; Ruffin, Edmund, 1794- 1865.; Conrad, Robert Young, 1805-1875.
Subjects:
Plantation life-- Virginia.; Horse-racing--Virginia.; Real property-- Virginia.; Virginia--Politics and government--1775-1861.; Slavery--Virginia.; Slavery--Southern States.; Tobacco-- Virginia.
Components List
  Series 1: People Files
- People Files, 1667-1862. (Folder 1-102)
    Subseries 1: Carter, Miss
  - Carter, Miss - Accounts, 1842., 2 items. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 2: Carter, (Miss C.)
  - Carter, (Miss C.) - Accounts, 1858., 1 item. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 3: Carter, (Charles) of Cleve, 1707-1764
  - Carter, (Charles) of Cleve, 1707-1764; 1747-1762., 3 items. (Folder 1)
    - Copy of will, 1762., 1 item. (Folder 1)
    - Papers showing descent of title to a messuage, houses and four lots on Palace Street, Williamsburg, from Charles Carter to Philip Grymes: Robert Cary to Kenneth Mackenzie, 1746-1751., 2 items. (Folder 1)
      - Deed, 1747., 1 item. (Folder 1)
        Note: This deed states that Robert Cary purchased the land from Charles Carter in 1746.
      - Deed from Kenneth Mackenzie to Philip Grymes, 1751., 1 item. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 4: Carter, (Charles) of Shirley, 1732-1806
  - Carter, (Charles) of Shirley, 1732-1806; 1788-1803., 5 items. (Folder 1)
    - Letters, 1788-1803., 4 items. (Folder 1)
      - T. Main, at London, [England], to Charles Carter, at Shirley, [Charles City County], Virginia, 16 Feb 1788 and 25 Feb 1788. (Folder 1)
        Two letters on same sheet.
      - W. Fitzhugh, at Chatham, to Charles Carter, at Shirley, [via] Bermuda Hundred, [Chesterfield County], 30 Nov 1796. (Folder 1)
      - Mary W. Braxton to her father, Charles Carter, at Shirley, 10 Feb 1803. (Folder 1)
      - William Beverley, at Richmond, to Charles Carter, at Shirley, 31 Dec 1803. (Folder 1)
    - Account, 1802. (Folder 1)
      Bill of lading for goods shipped from London to Charles Carter.
    Subseries 5: Carter, (Elizabeth) [wife of Landon Carter, 1792-1861]
  - Carter, (Elizabeth) [wife of Landon Carter, 1792-1861]- Epitaph, 1740., 1 item. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 6: Carter, (Elizabeth) [daughter of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861]
  - Carter, (Elizabeth) [daughter of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861] - Accounts, 1842-1849., 2 items. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 7: Carter, (Elizabeth L.) [sister of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861]
  - Carter, (Elizabeth L.) [sister of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861] - Accounts, 1822-1827., 12 items. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 8: Carter, (George) [son of Robert "Councillor" Carter]
  - Carter, (George) [son of Robert "Councillor" Carter] - Accounts, 1796-1812., 12 items. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 9: Carter, (George B.) estate
  - Carter, (George B.) estate, 1816-1820., 7 items. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 10: Carter, (John Armistead) guardianship
  - Carter, (John Armistead) guardianship, 1821-1851., 32 items. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 11: Carter, (Kate)
  - Carter, (Kate); 1849-1855., 2 items. (Folder 1)
    - Accounts, 1855., 1 item. (Folder 1)
    - School grades, Dec 1849., 1 item. (Folder 1)
    Subseries 12: Carter, (Landon), 1710-1778
  - Carter, (Landon), 1710-1778; 1729-1788., 61 items. (Folder 2-3)
    - Letters, 1737-1778., 17 items. (Folder 2)
      - John Carter, at Shirley, [Charles City County], to Landon Carter, at Landsdown, [Gloucester County], 12 Aug 1737., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Charles Carter to Landon Carter, 31 July 1738., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Philip Lightfoot, York [County], to Landon Carter, at Richmond, 30 July 1739., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Richard Parker to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, [Richmond County], 1 July 1763., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Robert Carter, at Williamsburg, to his brother [uncle?], Col. Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, 12 Feb 1764., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Charles Carter, at Cleve, [King George County], to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 31 March 1764., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Charles Carter, at Cleve, to Col. Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 31 March 1765., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Elizabeth Wormeley Berkeley to Col. Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 1 May 1765., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 2)
      - Maria Carter, at Cleve, to [Landon Carter], 2 June 1765., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Charles Carter, at Corotoman, [Lancaster County], to [Landon Carter], 4 Aug 1766., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - John Tayloe to Col. Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 3 Jan. 1768., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Robert Beverley, at Blandfield, [Essex County], to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 26 Feb 1771., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Edward Montagu, at London, to [Landon Carter?], 30 Sept 1772., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - W. Jones to Col. [Landon] Carter, at Sabine Hall, 1 Dec 1772., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, to "Wormeley the Elder," 25 Jan 1774., 1 item. (Folder 2)
        Draft of letter not sent.
      - Robert Beverley, at Blandfield, to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 27 July 1774., 1 item. (Folder 2)
      - I. William Giberne, at Belle-Ville, [Richmond County], to Col. Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 2)
        Note: A memorandum by Landon Carter, dated 3 May 1778, appears on back of sheet.
    - Papers, 1710-1778., 44 items. (Folder 3)
      Items are arranged into alphabetical order by last name.
      - Beckwith, (Elizabeth); 1735., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Power of attorney, Elizabeth Beckwith to Col. George Eskridge. Power of attorney for relinquishing her right of dower in a tract of land in Richmond County.
      - Beckwith, (Marmaduke); 1734., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Marmaduke Beckwith to Landon Carter. Lease of a tract of land in Richmond County.
      - Carter, Landon; 1736-1788., 28 items. (Folder 3)
        Papers concerning quitrents of Landon Carter, payable to Lord Fairfax.
      - Carter, Landon; 1738., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Appraisal of land in Richmond County lately belonging to Maj. Dennis McCarty, made by Robert Tomlin and William Dogges, at the request of Landon Carter.
      - Carter, Landon; 1752., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Surveyor's plat of the dividing line between the land of Landon Carter and John Kent, made by William Garland.
      - Carter, Landon; 1769., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Rough draft, written by Landon Carter, of a petition to the House of Burgesses regarding a proposed division of the counties of King George, Stafford, Richmond, and Westmoreland. (Counties of Virginia-Geography [1769]).
      - Carter, Landon; 1777., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 3)
        Notice concerning a runaway slave belonging to Landon Carter.
      - Carter, Landon; Feb. 1779., 1 item. Photostatic copy. (Folder 3)
        An inventory of the estate of Landon Carter, deceased.
      - Carter, Landon; May 1784., 5 items. (Folder 3)
        A list of papers of L[andon] C[arter], deceased, taken by Robert W. Carter.
      - Carter, Landon; n.d., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Speech of Landon Carter to a grand-jury.
      - Carter, Landon; n.d., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        A statement to the public by Landon Carter, regarding measures taken by England for the raising of revenues in the American colonies. The statement is addressed to Purdie and Dixon, [printers, Williamsburg].
      - Corotoman estate, Lancaster County; 1770., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Deposition of Landon Carter in a dispute, between Charles Carter of Corotoman and Robert Carter of Williamsburg, concerning possession of Corotoman estate.
      - Ring's Quarter, 1729., 1 item. (Folder 3)
        Surveyor's plat of a tract of land called "Ring's Quarter," in King and Queen County. Part of "Ring's Quarter" belonged to Mrs. Elizabeth Wormeley, whose daughter, Elizabeth, married Landon Carter.
    Subseries 13: Carter, (Landon, Jr.) [son of Landon Carter, 1710-1778]
  - Carter, (Landon, Jr.) [son of Landon Carter, 1710-1778] - Relinquishment of dower rights, 1793., 1 item. (Folder 4)
    Certificate of relinquishment of the dower rights of Nancy Jones, Wilks County, Georgia, to a tract of land in Northumberland County, Virginia, sold by her husband, Thomas Jones, to Landon Carter, Jr.
    Subseries 14: Carter, (Landon), 1756-1820, estate
  - Carter, (Landon), 1756-1820, estate; 1727-1858., 1049 items. (Folder 5-14)
    - Letters and correspondence concerning Landon Carter's estate, 1800-1820., 48 items. (Folder 5)
      - William Holburne, at Mount Airy, [Richmond County], to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 7 Nov 1800., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - Thomas Lud[well] Lee, at Coton, [Loudoun County], to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 26 Feb 1803., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - Thomas Lud[well] Lee, at Coton, [Loudoun County], to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, 24 Dec 1803., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - Landon Carter, Jr., at Sabine Hall, to Robert Patton, 24 Feb 1806., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 5)
      - John Law, at Washington, to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 16 Feb 1816., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - John Law, at Washington, to Landon Carter, at Richmond County Court House, Virginia, 30 Aug 1816., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - John Campbell to Landon Carter, and J. Harvey to Landon Carter, 28 Oct 1816., 1 item. (Folder 5)
        Both letters are on the same page.
      - L. N. Carter, at Washington, to his uncle, Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond Court House, Virginia, 4 Jan 1819., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - John Law, at Washington, to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County Court House, Virginia, 5 Jan 1819., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - Landon Carter, at Alexandria, to John Law, at Washington, 13 Aug 1819., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - M.M. Marmaduke, at Westmoreland Court House, to Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, 17 Jan 1820., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - Landon Carter, at Sabine Hall, to Thomas Brockenbrough, at Richmond, 14 Aug 1820., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - Landon Carter to [?] Tayloe, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 5)
      - Letters concerning the suit of Landon Carter vs. John Brown Cutting, 1814-1821., 10 items. (Folder 5)
      - Letters concerning the suit of Landon Carter vs. Johnson, 1847-1848., 3 items. (Folder 5)
      - Other letters concerning the estate of Landon Carter, 1820-1851., 22 items. (Folder 5)
    - Accounts of Landon Carter, 1756-1820., 725 items. (Folder 6-10)
      Includes one bound volume.
    - Papers, 1721-1855., 276 items. (Folder 11-14)
      - Plat of a tract of land in Northumberland County, 1804., 1 item. (Folder 11)
        Armistead (Lewis) - Plat of a tract of land in Northumberland County made by Rawleigh Tapscott at the request of Lewis Armistead.
      - Papers relating to the administration of the Landon Carter estate, 1804-1831., 6 items. (Folder 11)
        Beverley (Carter) - Papers relating to the dissatisfaction shown by Carter Beverley with Robert W. Carter's administration of the Landon Carter estate.
      - Court order for the appraisal of the estate of Landon Carter, 1820., 2 items. (Folder 11)
      - Agreement between Landon Carter and John D. Ficklin, manager at Clifton, 1820., 1 item. (Folder 11)
      - Request to the land office and reply, 1821., 2 items. (Folder 11)
        Robert W. Carter, administrator of Carter (Landon) - Request that the Land Office in Richmond furnish a copy of a deed establishing the line between the lands of [?] Sydnor and Landon Carter, and the reply to this request.
      - Carter (Landon) vs. William Brent et al, 1787-1852., 49 items. (Folder 11)
      - Carter (Landon) vs. John Gordon, William F. Gordon et al. Suit in Fredericksburg, 1797-1807., 3 items. (Folder 11)
      - Carter (Landon) to David Greenlaw. n.d., 1 item. (Folder 11)
        Extract of a deed.
      - Carter (Mary B.) et al vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter, 1822-1824., 4 items. (Folder 12)
        Suit in Fredericksburg.
      - Carter (Mary B.) et al vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter, 1842., 1 item. (Folder 12)
        Suit in Spotsylvania County.
      - Carter (Mary B.) vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter, 1851., 1 item. (Folder 12)
      - Carter (Mary B.) vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 12)
        Suit in Richmond District.
      - Carter (Robert W.) to John Campbell and John Tayloe Lomax. Trust deed for benefit of John Tayloe, 1820., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 12)
      - Carter (Robert W.) Refunding bonds taken by Robert W. Carter as administrator of Landon Carter, 1822., 6 items. (Folder 12)
      - Mathews (John R.) vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter, 1821., 2 items. (Folder 12)
        Suit in Richmond County.
      - Rust (Peter) to Landon Carter, 1806., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 12)
        Draft of a deed to a tract of land in Richmond County, called "Juggs."
      - Rust (Peter) to Landon Carter, 1806., 1 item. (Folder 12)
        Deed to a third part of a tract of land in Richmond County called "Juggs."
      - Rust (Peter) to Landon Carter, 1806., 1 item. (Folder 12)
        Draft of a deed to a tract of land in Richmond County.
      - Rust (Peter) to Landon Carter, 1806., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 12)
        Letter concerning a deed of trust given by Capt. Bramham and Peter Rust to Landon Carter.
      - Dispute between William H. Tayloe and Robert W. Carter concerning the line between their properties in Richmond County, 1842-1855., 6 items. (Folder 12)
        Tayloe (William H.) - Dispute.
      - Thompson (Mary) vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter, 1836-1837., 4 items. (Folder 12)
        Charles Mason, guardian of - Thompson (Mary) vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter. Suit in Spotsylvania County.
      - Tomlin (Walker) to Charles B. Carter, 1801., 1 item. (Folder 12)
        Deed to a tract of land in Richmond County, called "Hickory Thicket."
      - Tomlin (Williamson B.) and Ann C., his wife, et al vs. Robert W. Carter, administrator of Landon Carter, 1831., 1 item. (Folder 12)
      - Frederick County lands of Landon Carter, 1741-1858. (Folder 13)
        - Valuation and division, 1741-1847., 13 items. (Folder 13)
        - Portion of Landon Carter, Jr., 1834., 1 item. (Folder 13)
        - Portion of Mary B. Carter and income therefrom, 1827-1832., 18 items. (Folder 13)
        - Portion of Robert W. Carter, 1791-1858., 85 items. (Folder 13)
      - Loudoun County lands of Landon Carter, n.d., 2 items, including plat. (Folder 13)
        Includes a plat.
      - Papers relating to the portion of Mary B. Carter, 1821-1841., 60 items. (Folder 14)
        - Letters, 1825-1839., 10 items. (Folder 14)
        - Accounts, 1821-1841., 50 items. (Folder 14)
    Subseries 15: Carter, (Landon, Jr.) [half-brother of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861]
  - Carter, (Landon, Jr.) [half-brother of Robert W. Carter, 1792-1861] - Accounts, 1820-1850., 43 items. (Folder 15)
    Subseries 16: Carter, (Robert "King") 1663-1732
  - Carter, (Robert "King") 1663-1732; 1667-1730., 13 items. (Folder 16)
    The majority of the items relate to the papers of Robert "King" Carter.
    - Relinquishing of dower right belonging to Elizabeth Dickenson, 1714., 1 item. (Folder 16)
      Dickenson (Elizabeth) - Certificate appointing Austin Brockenbrough her attorney for relinquishing her right of dower in a tract of land in Richmond County sold by her husband, Thomas Dickenson, to Robert Carter.
    - Land patent and sureyor's plat belonging to Vincent Garner, 1728, n.d., 2 items. (Folder 16)
      Garner (Vincent) - Surveyor's plat of a tract of land in Northumberland County, belonging to Vincent Garner, 1728, and an undated memorandum of the bounds of Vincent Garner's land patent.
    - Deed - Jeffreys (Herbert) to Richard Custis, 1678., 1 item. (Folder 16)
      Deed to a tract of land in Lancaster County, adjoining Col. Carter's land.
    - Deed - Jenings (Edmund) to Robert Carter, 1718., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 16)
      Deed to a house and lot in Williamsburg.
    - Suit - Logan (Lawrence) lessee of Robert Carter vs. Isaac Allerton, by George Turberville, his guardian. 1730., 1 item. (Folder 16)
      Suit in Williamsburg. Note: It is possible that this Robert Carter is not Robert "King" Carter, but his son, Robert Carter of Nomini.
    - Trust deed - McCarty (Daniel) and Daniel Tebbs to Robert Carter, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 16)
      Trust deed covering a tract of land in Westmoreland County, called "Coles Land."
    - Lease of land - Neale (Rodham) to Robert Carter, 1713., 1 item. (Folder 16)
      Lease of a tract of land in Northumberland County.
    - Letter written from St. John Shropshire, Washington Parish, Westmoreland County, to Col. [Robert] Carter, 16 Aug 1705., 1 item. (Folder 16)
      Shropshire (St. John) - Re: recommending Richard Tankersly for a position.
    - Papers showing descent of title to a tract of land in Northumberland County from John Palmer to Robert Carter, 1667-1712., 4 items. (Folder 16)
      - Bill of Sale, 1667., 1 item. (Folder 16)
        John Palmer to David Ginnins [Jennings].
      - Will of David Jennings, 1675., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 16)
        Will of David Jennings, leaving his estate to Francis Bratton, whose daughter, Frances, afterwards married Enoch Hill.
      - Deed and Mortgage, 11 Oct 1712., 2 items. (Folder 16)
        Enoch Hill and Frances, his wife, to Robert Carter. Mortgage and deed to the same property, dated the same day.
    Subseries 17: Carter (Robert) of Nomini, born c. 1704, died 1731
  - Carter (Robert) of Nomini, born c. 1704, died 1731, 1712-1733., 5 items. (Folder 17)
    The majority of the items relate to the papers of Robert Carter of Nomini.
    Carter (Robert) of Nomini. Born c. 1704. Died 1731. [Son of Robert "King" Carter, and father of Robert "Councillor" Carter, of Nomini].
    - Quitrent certificate, from Fairfax (Catherine) baroness, granting to Robert Carter 1,989 acres of land in Northumberland County, 1712., 1 item. (Folder 17)
    - Letter - Hartshorne (William), at Alexandria, to Robert Carter, at Nomony [Nomini] Hall, [Westmoreland County], 26 April 1777., 1 item. (Folder 17)
      Letter concerning purchase of five tons of iron from Robert Carter.